Halt!
Identify yourself.
I am the wife of the Heir
to the Marquis of Shunan.
Open the city gates!
What is the purpose
of you leading your troops here
in the dead of night?
Forgive me,
but I am in armor and bound by duty.
I cannot let you pass.
(Rong)
I am under secret orders
from Noble Consort Rong
to mobilize the elite troops of
the Marquis of Shunan into the palace.
If we miss the designated time,
can you bear the consequences?
Open the gates immediately!
I will consider this your first offense
and deal with you leniently.
Deal with leniently?
Who do you think you are?
You...
I am the Heir to the Marquis of Shunan,
Bu Shulin's twin sister.
Nonsense!
Since when did he have a twin sister?
Xiao Wenxi,
you are indeed somewhat clever.
You've been pretending to be
educated, reasonable, and understanding.
I only found out after receiving
a secret letter from the Crown Princess
that you had
so many schemes and disguises.
I don't understand
what you're talking about.
You lured the tiger from the mountain,
and used the token to deceive
the Bu family's troops into serving you.
You intend to lead troops
into the imperial city
to assist Noble Consort Rong
in her coup.
If you dare to plot like this,
you should have asked
if I would allow it first.
What are you waiting for?
Hurry and arrest this imposter!
Do it!
Seize her!
Take her away!
Move!
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 35=
Thank you to the Shunan Army
for your full support.
You flatter us, Young Master Shen.
It is our duty.
I am under secret orders
from Princess Yaoxi
to lead the Lanhai soldiers here.
The Princess has ordered
that we are entirely at your disposal,
Young Master Shen.
The Crown Princess's safety
hangs by a thread.
Thank you both for your full support.
I am deeply grateful.
Soldiers, hear my command!
- Yes!
Follow me into the palace
to protect His Majesty!
Anyone who stands in my way
will be killed without mercy!
- Anyone who stands in my way
- will be killed without mercy!
Charge!
- Charge!
(Xuanming Gate)
Changqing,
stop this.
You can't keep making mistakes.
Whatever I do
has nothing to do with you.
Get out of my way.
I won't.
Today,
I will absolutely not let you pass.
Xiao Changying,
get out of my way!
I won't!
I'm warning you for the last time.
Do not interfere in anything.
Changqing,
do you know?
In my heart,
you are more important
than anything else in this world.
Others envy me for being born
into the royal family
and being able to grow up so carefree.
But I know
it's because I have
a strong older brother
who holds up the sky for me.
I once made two promises.
One was for Xihe.
Today,
I would rather die
than fail to keep her safe.
The second was for you.
In this life,
you and I are bound by blood.
I will never abandon you.
But now,
if you take one wrong step,
you will be doomed beyond redemption.
I don't want
to see you end up like that.
Changqing,
let us bring this to an end
right here!
Changying!
Guards,
throw him in the dungeon.
- Yes!
Changqing.
Changqing,
you can't go!
Xiao Changqing!
You can't!
Mother.
Qing,
are you all right?
What is the meaning of this, Prince Xin?
Do you really think
you still have a chance of winning?
Until the very last moment,
how can the winner be decided?
Hand over the edict.
In your dreams.
Do you really think
I would yield the throne to a child?
In today's battle,
I will not back down.
Fine.
Today, except for you,
everyone else will die here.
Guards!
Attack!
- Attack!
Report!
Your Highness,
the Shunan Army has entered the palace!
The Northwest Army and the Lanhai Army
have also broken in!
No.
Impossible.
You...
How did you send the message out?
(The Great Buddha Hall)
(Order)
(Prince Xin harbors
treasonous intentions.)
(Quickly summon Shen Yun'an,
Heir of the Duke of Wei, to the capital)
(to prepare for any contingencies.)
Besides His Majesty,
who else is in the bedchamber?
To answer Your Highness,
the Directorate of Astronomy,
the Chief Minister,
and several officials
from the Ministry of Rites are present.
They all entered by imperial decree.
The Assistant Directorate of Astronomy
and Vice Minister of Rites are waiting.
I happen to have some questions
for the Vice Minister of Rites.
Before seeing His Majesty,
may I have a word with him?
Yes, Your Highness.
I, Wu Shan, Vice Minister of Rites,
greet Your Highness.
(Wu Shan, Vice Minister of Rites)
May I ask why you
summoned me today?
I have a matter that requires you
to brave danger alone.
This matter is of utmost importance.
Are you willing to lend me a hand?
You may not know,
but the Crown Prince
previously instructed
that seeing the Crown Princess
is like seeing the Crown Prince himself.
Back then,
if the Crown Prince
hadn't overcome all objections
to appoint scholars
from humble backgrounds,
I would never be where I am today.
Furthermore, we from humble families
all rely on His Highness's grace
in promoting the underprivileged
and appointing only the virtuous.
Only then could
our lifelong ambitions be realized.
A scholar dies for his confidant.
The task you entrust to me,
I will not decline
even if it means my death.
Good.
My brother is waiting at Mount Ziyun
in the suburbs of the capital.
Go there personally
and tell him to immediately
contact Young Master Bu
and Consort Shu's personal guards
to enter the palace at once
to protect the Emperor.
The city is heavily guarded
inside and out right now.
The road ahead is extremely dangerous.
I'll leave this to you, Minister Wu.
I am familiar with the trails
in the suburbs.
I will definitely not fail this mission.
Please rest assured, Your Highness.
You had already planned
to fight me to the death.
You could have
avoided coming to this.
Xihe!
Let's go.
Get down! Don't move!
The palace is under control!
None of the rebels will escape!
Good work, Yun'an!
- Greetings, Your Highness.
- We, the soldiers of the three armies,
- will follow Your Highness's orders!
- We await your command!
- We will follow Your Highness's orders!
Please rise, everyone.
- Yes, Your Highness!
Rebels of the Rong family,
your cause is lost.
Putting up a stubborn resistance
will only lead to your deaths.
Considering that you
may have been coerced,
lay down your weapons immediately,
and your families' lives will be spared.
If you remain obstinate,
the Embroidered Envoy is here.
You will be killed without mercy.
We were all forced by
Noble Consort Rong!
We surrender!
- We surrender!
Qing.
Qing, stop.
We have completely lost.
I beg you.
Mother.
I have failed you.
Qing!
Take him away.
(Qing)
I have something
to say to the Crown Princess alone.
What do you want to say?
I know your capabilities.
As long as you want to,
you can rule as the Empress Dowager.
But for a woman to rule the world,
this path
will be very difficult for you.
Now,
you have saved the officials
from the sword.
From now on,
no matter what you want to do,
no one will dare
to say a word against it.
Are you saying
that all of this,
from forcing me to marry you
to us crossing swords,
was done by you on purpose?
Between you and me,
we were destined to be incompatible.
Your biggest obstacle
was me, Xiao Changqing.
But now,
I am a treasonous rebel.
All your obstacles
will cease to exist.
I'll go get an imperial physician.
Don't.
In the last moments of my life,
I want to look at you.
I told you a long time ago
that I could face it myself.
Why did it have to come to this?
I know my own heart very well.
As long as I am alive,
I can't let you go.
I can't stop myself
from getting close to you.
My existence,
and my obsession,
will eventually become your shackles.
Only if I die
can we both be free.
♪The stars are sinking
like a sunken vow♪
♪You drifted away alone♪
♪Without a single word of goodbye♪
♪Leaving no room to turn back♪
I once promised
that I could give up everything for you,
and protect you with my life.
Last time,
I failed to do so.
But this time,
I finally didn't let you down.
♪Where water and sky whisper as one♪
♪Life and death are but a moment apart♪
♪Let fate scheme and pull the strings♪
♪Grudges will find their own end♪
♪The human heart is harder
to read than any chessboard♪
♪I step onto this winding path♪
♪What was swept away?♪
Could you... Could you
grant a dying person
one last wish?
Please?
Answer me one question.
Tell me.
Are you Gu Qingzhi?
Are you?
♪You drifted away alone♪
♪Without a single word of goodbye♪
♪Leaving no room to turn back♪
♪I can only stay there forever♪
♪In the coming years, I'll always
remember that year, my graceful lover♪
♪Love hangs on the crest of the waves♪
The day I first met you,
it was raining like this, too.
♪All farewells are stranded
in the middle of the night♪
That's nice.
♪Not enough to move heaven and earth♪
♪A lifetime feels too short♪
♪Watching the vast sea of flowers
scattered like stars♪
♪While I stand on this shore,
wrapped in memories♪
♪A hand I cannot touch♪
♪I hold it for a moment
in the reflection♪
♪A hand I cannot touch♪
♪I hold it for a moment♪
♪In the reflection♪♪
(Chenning Hall)
Your Majesty.
Just now,
the Crown Prince
you single-handedly groomed
attempted to rebel.
Impossible.
Changqing
would never commit treason.
He has already been executed.
Anyone who dares to usurp the throne
will meet this end.
Your sons are leaving you one by one.
Does it break your heart?
Mother,
why did you do this?
Your Highness, you have been waiting
for this moment,
haven't you?
Yes.
For this day,
I have waited for over twenty years.
And it's because of you
that I fell short at the last hurdle.
When did you
start suspecting me?
Gu Qingshu was just a helpless orphan.
Those risky schemes
must have had someone backing them.
The person
of the highest status around her
was you.
More importantly,
the poisonous incense she hid
in my golden lock
was made
by modifying a rare incense
from the Western Regions.
The base of that incense formula
was the calming incense
you frequently use.
It is unique in the palace.
Thinking about it carefully,
why would Gu Qingshu dare
to instigate the Second Prince
to oppose the East Palace?
How did the Fourth Prince secretly
enter the palace to assassinate?
How could he incite
the Imperial Guard to rebel?
And the deaths of Consort Liang
and the Second Prince.
Every single incident
is connected to you.
Mother,
why did you do this?
Because...
Because I am full of hate.
Did you know
that the Crown Prince always
respected his grandmother?
In his heart,
besides His Majesty,
you were his closest family.
He never once suspected
that you would poison him.
The poison given to Huayong
was your doing?
Yes.
Who asked him to be
the Emperor's most favored son?
Back then,
you stood on the city wall
and refused to send reinforcements,
watching helplessly as Prince Qian,
my own biological son,
fought a lone battle
and died on the battlefield.
It's been twenty years.
Not a day goes by
that I don't think of him.
I also know Huayong is innocent.
I couldn't bear it either.
But whenever I think of my son
who died unjustly,
my heart breaks.
Mother...
Huayong is not my flesh and blood.
He is Juewei's own flesh and blood.
He is your own grandson.
Before Prince Qian died for his country,
he entrusted me with this.
Tomorrow,
the enemy's main force will attack.
I will lead the troops out of the city.
You will defend the city.
Remember our agreement.
One signal means come to my aid.
Two signals
mean defend to the death.
This is a military order.
I will not fail you.
It's the signal.
It's my brother's signal.
Gather the troops and open the gates!
Ride to Prince Qian's aid!
- Wait!
- Yes!
Hurry!
Hold on.
Two signals.
How could it be two signals?
Pass on my order.
All soldiers
defend the city to the death!
What are you saying?
- Duke Ying!
Don't be impulsive.
Prince Qian is surrounded right now!
Are we just going to leave him to die?
Archers, nock your arrows!
The city gates
must never be opened!
Are you going to watch Prince Qian
die on the battlefield
with your own eyes?
He is your brother!
Your brother!
This is a life-and-death pact
between my brother and me.
Anyone who opens the gates
without authorization
will be executed without mercy!
Juewei.
Juechong.
Yunzhou City
is the strategic chokepoint
of the northwest.
You must hold it.
You must never
let the people fall into misery.
But you are the future Crown Prince.
You need to return
to the imperial capital.
You cannot die here.
Trading my life
for a shred of the people's trust
in the court
and a shred of hope for the future.
If I die here,
it will be a worthy death.
Juewei, you have the people
in your heart.
But I
only have you in my heart.
When I was young,
in the palace,
I was an insignificant person.
Only you
noticed the emptiness in my heart,
and gave me dignity.
All that I could do for you
was just provide you
with material things
and keep up your appearances
just like me.
But this one time,
I don't want you
to be like me.
No.
No, Juewei.
Live on well.
No.
Juewei, you have to hold on.
You have to hold on!
My wife
is about to give birth.
Take good care
of her and the child.
Juewei.
Juewei!
I...
I deserve to die a thousand deaths.
Sister-in-law...
What happened to her?
The Princess Consort
heard of Prince Qian's passing
and was overcome with grief.
It affected her pregnancy.
The bleeding wouldn't stop.
Just now,
she passed away.
Sister-in-law,
I am useless.
I couldn't bring my brother back.
Your Highness.
The little imperial grandson
has been born.
Should we send a message immediately
to inform the Empress?
Princess Consort Qian has passed away.
The unborn child could not be saved.
Both mother and child
have perished.
But Your Highness,
- the imperial grandson is clearly...
- I said,
both mother and child have perished.
Your Highness.
Guards.
Here, Your Highness.
These people in the room
disrespected
the Princess Consort's remains
and harbored malicious intent.
Dispose of them cleanly.
Leave no trace.
Understood.
- Your Highness!
- Spare us, Your Highness!
From now on,
you are my child.
- Long live, Your Majesty.
Official Zhao brought a package
from outside the palace.
He insisted it be handed
to you in person.
I'm really curious.
What kind of person was my father?
Your father,
in my heart,
was a perfect man.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)